《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
各位，我们要出发了
Hey, y'all, we're headed out, man.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-希望你找到女友，伙伴 -宝贝，到底怎么回事？
- I hope you find the girl, buddy. - Baby, what the hell's going on?
赫特说你可能 无法假释出狱
Hector says that you could serve your full sentence.
-你来做什么？犸丽在哪里？ -她现在是我的
- What you doing here? Where's Maricruz? - She's with me now.
你说快回家是什么意思？ 该不会是让女儿空欢喜吧？
What's this I hear about you coming home? You getting your daughter's hopes up?
你现在坐着吗？
You sitting down?
你的丈夫这礼拜就要回家了
Your man is coming home this week.
我们可以从这里走路去法院
We can make it to the courthouse on foot.
你不懂，所有东西都在车上
You don't understand. Everything is in that car.
我已经戒毒18个月
I've been clean for 18 months now.
我希望帮助沉沦的人 和我一样改过自新
I wanna help people get from where I've been to where I am.
你说得对 我不该把你牵扯进来
You're right. I should never have gotten you involved.
我要知道你用什么条件
I just need to know what Michael scofield...
和麦可史柯菲交换绿卡
...wanted from you in exchange for the green card.
卡洛琳，我做这行已经15年 我一直都在
Caroline, I've been doing this for 15 years, it's never been about anything...
替你和你的家人效命 更重要的是替国家效命
...other than you, your family and most importantly, this country.
我要知道我到底是替谁工作
Now, I need to know who I'm working for here,
你是替我工作
You are working for me.
关于监狱工厂的事宜
Are you aware of any arrangement officer Bellick had...
贝里克狱警 是否有和犯人勾结？
...with any inmate regarding Prison Industries?
有，他把工作权 卖给约翰亚布兹
Yeah, he sold it to John Abruzzi.
布拉德贝里克狱警 你被开除了，立即生效
Officer Brad Bellick to be terminated, effective immediately.
电视上刚宣布赏金
They just announced the rewards on the TV.
-多少钱？ -一个犯人十万美金
- How much? - A hundred thousand dollars apiece.
钱就在犹他州图尔附近
The money. Just outside of Tooele, Utah.
-我盯住他了 -他在墙上
- I got him. - He's on the wall!
上卡车
Truck!
派人到附近所有的医院 不管他们在哪，其中一人伤得不轻
Get men at all the area hospitals. Wherever they are, one of them's bleeding good.
-我们得快点离开 -我没办法
- We gotta move. - I can't.
这么辛苦计划，再逃出监狱
Put in all that work, break out of prison...
最后却死在河床底
...only to end up dead at the bottom of a ditch.
还真有点悲哀
Kind of sad, really.
他是哥哥还是弟弟？
So which one of them was it?
（12小时前）
所有医院已经布下天罗地网
We got a blanket on all the hospitals.
免费诊所呢？
Free clinics?
只要能包扎或擦药的地方 我们都有派人
If they got Band-Aids and Bactine, we got a body in there.
这对兄弟如果去就医 就等着被送回福克斯河州立监狱
The brothers come in for a medical, they're getting it in a van back to Fox River.
其他六人有新消息吗？
Anything break on the other six?
正在监控他们的家人 目前没有动静，也许他们正在躲藏
Eyes and ears on the families. So far, no hits. Maybe just laying low.
犯人最难做到的事是什么？
What's the hardest thing in the world for a con to do?
没有吗？
Nothing?
-人生有两件事逃不了，你是K -兰恩
- Two things in life are certain, Miss? - Lang.
死亡、煤税 还有一个逃亡的人
Death, taxes and the fact that a man on the run...
在前72小时一定会犯错
...will make a mistake in the first 72 hours.
需要逃到远处，就会偷车 需要钱，就会去抢劫商店
Needing distance, he'll steal a car. Needing money, he'll rob a store.
需要帮助 就会信任不该信任的人
Needing help, he'll trust someone that he shouldn't.
而当他犯错时
And when he does...
就会留下线索，引导我们找到他
...he will leave behind the crumbs that will take us right to him.
-我需要你帮忙 -麦可，怎么回事？
- I need your help. - Michael, what are you doing?
-红辣椒粉 -什么？
- Cayenne pepper. - What?
你厨房里有红辣椒粉吗？
In your kitchen, do you have any?
也许有
Yeah, maybe.
我需要消毒酒精、毛巾和止痛剂
I'm gonna need some rubbing alcohol, some towels and painkillers.
-你有什么都拿来 -还有酒
- Whatever you got. - And some booze.
求求你
Please.
慢慢来K
Easy, easy. Easy, easy.
慢慢来
Easy.
没有大碍的，我们继续逃
It's fine, man. Let's just keep moving.
继续逃的话 你的腿会继续流血
We keep moving and that leg keeps bleeding.
你的腿不止血 我们就逃不出伊利诺州
That leg keeps bleeding and we're not getting out of Illinois.
这会很痛
This is gonna hurt.
很好K
That's good, that's good, that's good.
这可以让微血管闭合
This will seal the capillaries.
麦可，你不能来这里
You should not have come here.
警察已经来问过我
The police have been here asking questions.
我们别无选择
We didn't have a choice.
我很感谢你帮我得到绿卡 可是我不想被牵扯进来K
I'm thankful for the help with the green card but I just don't wanna get involved...
这不是之前的协议 我知道K对不起
It wasn't part of our deal. I know, I know. I'm sorry.
对不起 我们没有其他地方可去
I'm sorry. There was nowhere else to go.
我看到新闻的时候，我很担心
When I saw you on the news, I was worried.
我那能希望你们已经跨越边境了
I just hoped you'd crossed the border by now.
我也这么希望
So did I.
继续给他吃这个
Keep giving him these.
-看能不能帮他找件干净衣服 -好
- See if you can find him some clean clothes. - Okay.
我得回去开车子
I gotta go back and get our car.
别管那辆车子，我们再找一辆
Forget the car. We can get another.
不能随便一辆车 我需要那辆车
I don't need a car, I need that car.
为什么？
Why?
因为车上有帮助我们 消失的一切
Because in that car is everything we need to disappear.
-有何发现？ -这里，老大
- What have you got? - Here we go, boss.
警察几小时前 抓到一个流浪汉
One of the blues hauled in a vagrant a couple of hours ago.
看来他身上有些东西
It seems the man was in possession of an item or two...
是偷来的
...that didn't exactly belong to him.
看来我们找到第一个错误了
Looks like we got our first mistake.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：收音机疑云
你们有那种东方肉干吗？
Hey, you got any of that oriental jerky?
什么？
Excuse me?
照烧口味的
Teriyaki flavor.
没有
No.
那后面有吗？
Well, you got any in the back?
我看看
Let me check.
顺便帮我拿一瓶威士忌，小弟
And get me a bottle of that Early Times while you're back there, junior.
你今天可以工作久一点 看着店面，我马上回来
Feel free to earn your paycheck today. Watch the store, I'll be right back.
你好吗，罗伊？
How goes it, Roy?
说真的，罗伊 你大可不必踢我跨下
To be honest, Roy, I could've done without the knee to the junk.
你咬了我，布拉德 像个小女孩一样
You bit me, Brad. Like a little girl, you bit me.
-那是你应得的 -大概是吧
- Well, you had it coming. - Yeah, probably did.
真是荒唐 我们为了事情的结果互相怪罪
You know, it's crazy, us taking it out on each other for how things turned out.
你想怪罪人的话 何不怪那些每天早上
You want someone to blame, how about those convicts staring up at us...
从报纸里盯着我们的罪犯？
...from the papers every morning?
他们害我丢掉工作、退休金、尊严
They took my job, my pension, my dignity.
他们翻墙出去时 那些都被他们一并带走了
When they went over that wall, they took all of it right along with them.
我一生辛苦的成果
Everything I worked for my whole life.
你有看到逮捕他们的赏金吗？
You see that reward they got?
那些浑蛋死了 都比你我活着要值钱
Those ass-hats are worth more dead than you and I are alive.
-维持不了多久的 -什么意思？
- Not for long. - What do you mean?
有人一定会拿到赏金 还不如由我来拿
I mean somebody's gonna get that money. Might as well be me.
你知道，这种工作
You know, a job like that...
如果多个帮手会顺利许多
...might go a little smoother with an extra pair of hands.
你真以为我会和你平分赏金？
You really think I'm gonna split that reward with you?
我是指等你找到那对兄弟 他们人多势众
I'm just saying, you run into those brothers, two of them, one of you...
到时你会需要帮手在一旁
...you might find yourself wishing for a good wingman.
快完成，麦可
Just get it done, Mike.
-你好吗？ -我能效劳吗？
- How you doing? - Can I help you?
希望可以，查克
Yeah, I hope so, Chuck.
你们拖走我的车了
I think you may have towed my car.
-什么样的车？ -什么样的车？
- What'd it look like? - What did it look like?
你偷背包的车子 长的是什么样子？
The car you stole the backpack from, what did it look like?
不知道，也许是灰色的吧
I don't know, man. Maybe it was gray.
-灰色本田雅哥 -车牌呢？
- It's a gray Accord. - License number?
听着，我只知道这些
Look, man, that's all I know.
我要偷的不是车
I wasn't after the car.
-我以为背包里面有衣服 -你记得车子停在哪里吗？
- I thought the bag had some clothes in it. - You remember where the car was parked?
你停在哪里？
Where'd you park it?
汉卡街和15街路口
Corner of Hancock and 15th.
不知道，也许在15街附近
I don't know, maybe around 15th somewhere.
-可是车子不会在那里 -什么意思？
- But it ain't gonna be there anymore. - What do you mean?
那就是我为何 没有偷其他东西的原因
That's the reason I didn't get to grab anything else.
-拖吊车刚好过来 -我已经在查了
- Tow truck rolled up. - Already on it.
好，拖吊费60美金
Okay, it's gonna be 60 bucks for the tow...
隔夜保管费24美金
...and 24 for the overnight.
好，我去开你的车
All right. I'll be right back with your vehicle.
应该几分钟就好
Shouldn't take but a few minutes.
（俄亥俄州，迪法恩斯）
- Hello, - Petey, it's sucre.
-你好 -彼提，我是苏克
你是费南多苏克？
As in Fernando Sucre?
-还有另一个吗？ -希望不会有
- Is there another one? - Man, I hope not,
但是我朋友苏克 不会打电话给我
But my boy, sucre, would not be calling me on the telephone...
害我成为他的蠢越狱行动共犯
...thereby making me an accessory to his dumb-ass escape, man.
抱歉老哥，我K 需要你帮我连络犸丽
I'm sorry, bro, I just need you to get ahold of Maricruz.
我不能打给她 那里有一堆调查局员在
I can't call her cell because the feds will be all over the place.
听着，你一定要忘了那个女孩
Homes, listen, man, you have got to forget about that girl.
白痴，要是我忘了她 我现在还会
If I could forget about her, pendejo, I'd still be at Fox River...
呆坐在福克斯河监狱的烂床上
...sitting in cell 40 on your old bunk.
好吧，希望你现在站得很稳 我要告诉你一个消息
I hope you're holding onto something tight because I'm about to break it down for you.
她星期六就要和赫特结婚
She's getting married to Hector on saturday.
-今天是星期几？ -星期四
- What day's today? - Thursday, bro.
很抱歉
Sorry, man,
好吧
All right.
-今晚一定要把她带到你家 -等等K
- You gotta get her to your place tonight. - But hang on, man,
我只有最后的机会 让她改变心意
I got one last shot to make her change her mind, dude.
设法让她过去，好吗？
Just find a way to get her there, okay?
等等，苏克，等一下
Wait, sucre, hang on, man.
车子的K窗户破了
About the broken window...
我们墙上有贴免责声明 不须负责K
We got a disclaimer posted on the wall, says we're not res...
我不在乎车窗破了，查克
I don't care about the broken window, Chuck.
车里有一个背包
I had a backpack inside.
我们拖车时没看到
Not when we got it.
有一些文件要你填一下
Got some paperwork for you to fill out.
你很眼熟
You look familiar.
我K刚当护士时 你是驻院医生
Yeah, you were the attending when I first started here.
好
Sure.
你们可以帮我叫计程车吗？
Would one of you mind calling me a cab, please?
我没办法
I don't think so.
丹奎迪医生，我K
Look, Dr. Tancredi, l...
-我只想祝你好运 -莎拉丹奎迪？
- I just wanna say good luck. - Sara Tancredi?
-对不起 -你有权保持沉默
- I'm sorry. - You have the right to remain silent.
请把手放到后方
Please place your hands behind your back.
你们如果还有疑问，我很乐意K
If you have any questions, I'm happy to come down.
丹奎迪小姐，因为我尊重你父亲 我要再问一次
Ms. Tancredi, out of respect for your father, I'm gonna ask you again.
我父亲？
My father?
我相信他会希望 能够和平逮捕你
I'm sure he'd prefer that this went without incident.
在警方侦讯前 你有权先找律师
You have the right to speak to an attorney before you speak to the police.
你说的一切都会成为呈堂证供
Anything you say may be used against you in a court of law.
你现在和以后的侦讯 都可以有律师陪同
You may have an attorney present during questioning now or in the future.
卡洛琳，警察把她带走了
Caroline, they're taking her in.
当然，我会盯着她
Of course, I'll keep an eye on her.
你只要在下面签名
All you gotta do is sign here at the bottom.
你就可以走了，失陪
You'll be one your way. Excuse me, please.
-布斯特拖吊厂 -我是调查局的曼宏特别探员
- Brewster's Towing. - This is Agent Mahone with the FBI.
-请问大名？ -查克
- Who am I speaking with? - Chuck.
我要通知你一个可能的情况 你有在听吗，查克？
I wanna alert you to a possible situation. Are you listening to me, Chuck?
有人可能会去领一辆车
An individual may be coming there to inquire about a vehicle,
一辆灰色本田雅哥 后车窗可能破了
A gray Accord, probably with a busted rear window,
有人过去寻找 符合描述的车吗？
Has anyone come by looking for a vehicle that matches that description?
-有的 -什么时候？
- Yes, sir. - When?
查克，告诉我他何时去的？
Chuck, can you tell me when he was there?
现在
Right now.
史柯菲在布斯特拖吊厂
Brewster's Towing. Scofield's there.
查克，不要让他走
Chuck, stall him.
各小组，监狱逃犯史柯菲 被目击出现在布斯特拖吊厂
All units, Fox River subject 01 scofield, V-ID'd at Brewster's Towing.
是我的老板 他同意后我才能放车
It's my supervisor. He says I gotta get clearance before I can release the car.
查克，你在吗？查克
Chuck, you there? Hey, chuck,
快点，查克，你还在线上吗？
Come on. Come on, Chuck. You still with me?
等你来 那辆车可能已经不在了
Yeah, that vehicle might not be here when you get here.
你得立刻派人来
You need to send somebody now.
不能让他走
Do not let him leave!
钥匙被他拿走了
Oh, he got the keys.
-警车到哪去了？ -还有六到七分钟才能到，长官
- Where the hell are those units? - Still six or seven minutes out, sir.
监听到富兰克林在通话
We got chatter. It's Franklin.
他在市区打公共电话 第二个错误
He's at a payphone downtown. Mistake number two.
（伊利诺州，芝加哥）
I know. Just let me explain, all right?
我知道K让我解释好吗？
你真的从军过吗？
Were you ever even in the military?
我替国家效命 国家却反咬我一口，好吗？
I served my country and my country served me up, all right?
我也希望此刻能够 全盘对你说清楚
Now, look, I wish I could lay this all out for you right here, right now.
我只想说我很抱歉，我爱你
But just know, baby, I am sorry and I love you,
等时机一到，我会解释清楚
And when the time comes, I will explain everything,
给我一个 不该立刻报警的理由
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't turn you in right now.
我可以给你三个理由
You know what? I'll give you three.
我、你 还有我们美丽的小女儿
Me, you and that beautiful little girl of ours.
宝贝，我有个计划
Baby, look, I got a plan.
我有个计划，能凑到一些钱
I got a plan that is gonna get us some money...
让你我和小孩到一个 永远不会有人打扰的地方
...where you and I and the baby, nobody can ever find us or bother us again.
你一定要相信我 我只要你给我机会听我说
You gotta trust me. That's all I need, is the opportunity for you to hear me out.
可以吗？
All right?
好
All right.
好，听着 有人找你问过我的事吗？
All right, listen. Has anybody tried to contact you about me?
-没有 -好
- No. - Okay,
好，很好K
Okay, that's good, that's good,
听着
Listen,
在彩虹厅里面
In the Rainbow Room...
那是纽约市的一家餐厅
Restaurant, New York City.
你记得我们拍照 那个美丽的地点吗？
- Do you remember that beautiful spot where we took that picture?
窗户旁边那里？
The one by the window?
一个礼拜后我会去那里等着
I am going to be waiting in that spot one week from now.
在这整个世界上 我只希望K
And that's all that I want...
我的两个女孩在那里等我
...in this whole world, is for my two girls to be waiting there for me.
-你听懂了吗？ -听着，我得挂了
- Do you understand what I'm saying? - Look, I gotta go.
宝贝，我只想知道 你会过去吗？
Baby, I just wanna know, are you going to be there?
我不知道
I don't know,
但你很了解我的
But you know me.
-真的吗？ -当然
- Do I? - Yes.
再见，迈尔斯
Goodbye, Miles.
我会通知曼哈顿分局
I'll alert the office in Manhattan.
把富兰克林的照片 拿给每个彩虹厅员工
Send Franklin's picture to the Rainbow Room.
之后去和他的妻子谈谈 女人的谈话
And go have a chat with his wife, woman to woman.
问她为何从未去 福克斯河监狱探望丈夫
Ask her why she never visited her husband at Fox River.
假装你不知道答案 他们的关系很脆弱
Pretend you don't know, the relationship is fragile.
我们不停碰脆弱的地方 她就会招供
We keep tapping the cracks and she's gonna break.
是，长官 感谢你交付我任务
Yes, sir. I appreciate the assignment. I want you to...
兰恩，我不需要感激 我需要的是线索、答案和进展
Lang, I don't need gratitude. I need leads, answers, progress.
没办法给我的人，就等着离开
Anybody that can't deliver that, just don't even unpack.
-清楚了吗？ -是，长官
- Clear? - Yes, sir.
-卫勒先生 -稍等
- Mr. Wheeler. - Stand by.
继续查史柯菲 我要那辆雅哥的车牌号码
Stay on scofield. I want the license plate number of that Accord...
然后我要你通知各单位
...and I want you to get it out on the wire.
-请说 -现在去办
- Yeah. - Now.
我再打给你
I'll call you back.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
显然不是只有我在找这辆车
Apparently, I wasn't the only one looking for this car.
太好了，我们快走
Great. Let's get out of here.
很抱歉把你牵扯进来
I'm sorry I had to involve you in this.
我是指害你牵扯得更深
I mean, any more than I already have.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你也是
To you too.
那么K
So...
我们以后再见
I'll see you.
希望如此
I hope so.
-你没事吧？ -没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
好
Good.
我们要往西走，去找钱和罗杰
We're heading west, toward the money, toward L.J.
出发前要再去一个地方
Just got one more stop to make.
你要做什么？
What for?
你信任我吗？
You trust me?
布拉德，我当然信任你
Of course, I trust you, Brad.
但K要是有人发现，我就K
It's just that if anybody finds out about this, l...
不会有人发现的
They won't.
交给我去办
Let me handle this.
蛋头憨博弟爬上墙
Humpty Dumpty climbed up a wall
蛋头憨博弟重重地摔下来
Humpty Dumpty had a great fall,
听着，我已经告诉过调查局 我什么都不知道
Look, I already told the feds, I don't know anything, okay?
你说那些穿高级皮鞋的西装男？ 何必对他们说实话？
Those suits with pedicures and penny loafers? Why would you?
他们有规矩要遵守 操守和准则
They got rules to follow, codes of conduct.
他们得保住工作
They got jobs to protect.
-至于我就不用了 -别这样，老大
- Now me, on the other hand... - Come on, boss.
我发誓 他们的计划都没有告诉我
I swear, those guys didn't let me in on any plans.
你是说那个小团体在操场时
Are you telling me that in all your little powwows in the yard...
他们一次也没提到，翻过墙后
...they never once mentioned what they were gonna do...
他们打算要去哪里？
...once they went over that wall?
没错
That's right.
我也许已经不是狱警，小胖
I may not work here anymore, big-uns...
但我对他们还是有点影响力
...but I still got influence with people who do.
只要我要求，他们就会做到 要修理谁都可以
People who will do whatever I ask them to, to whoever I ask them to.
像你这种丰满的男人
And a curvy man like yourself...
我想一定有些心理不正常的人
Let's just say there's some filthy individuals...
会喜欢和女人相似的狱友
...who might enjoy a cellie with womanly attributes.
你现在就把 知道的一切都告诉我
Now, you're gonna tell me everything you know...
告诉我这些逃犯打算逃亡到哪里
...about where those convicts are headed...
否则我就把你 这只肥羊丢入虎口
...or I'm gonna throw your fat ass to the wolves.
好，谢谢
Okay, thanks.
出现第三个错误
Mistake number three.
有人通报说看见疑似 费南多苏克的人偷车
Someone reported seeing a man matching Fernando sucre's description stealing a car.
-在哪里？ -俄亥俄州迪法恩斯
- Where? - Defiance, ohio.
今天一定有人会被逮捕
Someone's going down today.
修女，我知道K
I know, mami, I know.
莎拉
Sara.
-我帮你付了保释金 -还真花了你不少时间
- I paid your bail. - You took your time.
-我是州长，我有事要忙K -去死吧，爸
- I'm the governor. I do have things that... - Go to hell, Dad.
你的态度再如此恶劣 也许以后我只能在这见到你
You keep this up, this may be the only place I'll be able to see you.
你有想要听我的说辞吗？
Do you even wanna hear my side of things?
莎拉，我没有很想
Not particularly, sara, no.
尤其是当我 根本不清楚你站在哪一方时
Especially when I have no idea whose side you're on.
但有一点我很清楚
But I do know this.
福克斯河越狱事件 有人一定要负责
Somebody is gonna go down because of what happened at Fox River.
如果那个人不是你
And it would be in both of our best interests...
对我们俩都最好
...if that someone was not you.
但为了确保这种结果 必须采取一定步骤
But to ensure this, certain steps need to be taken.
第一，  你得参加每日戒毒会
One, you should go to a daily recovery meeting.
第二，你必须对法官宣称无罪
Two, you need to go before a judge and plead not guilty.
-第三K -我不行K
- And three... - Dad, I don't...
你必须把实情 一五一十告诉矫正局
You need to tell the DoC everything you know...
说出监狱是如何管理的
...about how that prison was being run.
波普典狱长 让史柯菲享有特权
And that Warden Pope, how he was granting favors to scofield...
因为史柯菲私底下帮他忙
...because scofield helped him with his personal projects.
因此让他有机会 进入某些禁区
Thereby exposing him to certain restricted areas...
让他有办法取得医务室的钥匙
...where he may have been able to obtain a key to the infirmary.
我办不到
I can't do that.
莎拉，你当然办得到 你会这么说的
Oh, yes, you can, sara. You can do that and you will.
是我做的，爸
I did it, Dad.
我刻意没锁门，是我一个人做的
I left the door open. Me, and no one else.
这不是真的
That's not true.
-是真的 -不是真的
- Yes, it is. - That's not true.
莎拉
Sara...
照我的话去做
...just do what you're told.
否则后果会影响到我们俩
Otherwise, there will be consequences that will affect us all.
你懂我的意思吗？
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
懂，先生
Yes, sir.
很好
Good.
在一周后
In one week...
我会被指派 成为新任的美国副总统
...I will be appointed the new vice president of the United states.
我们会举行典礼，他们会邀请你
There will be a ceremony, you will be invited.
但是你不要参加
You will not attend.
再见，莎拉
Goodbye, sara.
-放音乐来听 -不要碰
- Let's put some music on. - No.
我忘了，不能开收音机
Forgot. No radio.
外面真是安静
Man, it's quiet out here.
监狱里到处都是噪音
Inside, there was always noise, you know.
喊叫声、狱警巡察声 我已经习惯了
Someone yelling, guards making rounds. Kind of got used to it.
说得对，还是回监狱好了
You're right. We should go back.
你的刺青 不只是用来越狱的吧？
The tats. They weren't just for getting out, were they?
逃出来只是开端 现在将会更有趣
Breaking out was just the beginning. Now it gets a little more interesting.
因为我被绑在电椅上 还不够有趣？
Because me being strapped to the electric chair wasn't interesting enough.
我只是说 在监狱里有意外的惊喜
All I'm saying, is inside, we had the element of surprise.
没有人知道我们的计划
No one knew what we were planning.
可是电梯里的那个特务 感觉不简单
But there's something about this guy, the one in the elevator.
就像是K
It's like...
他知道我们要去哪 看穿我们的心思
It's like he knows where we're going, what we're thinking,
如果是真的，他早晚 会知道犹他州的钱
It's a matter of time before he finds out about the money in Utah,,,
波修伊布斯 我们逃到墨西哥的通道
,,, Bolshoi Booze, our way into Mexico,
他全都会知道
Everything.
你准备好了吗？
You ready for this?
打电话吧
Make the call.
请留言
Please leave a message,
是我
Hey. It's me.
我救到林克了 我们正要过去那里
I've got Linc. We're on our way there.
如果你没办法过去 打917454K
Lf, for some reason, you can't make it, call me back at 917-454...
监听组刚刚送来的
Just got this from surveillance.
记得史柯菲坐牢前 预付的语音信箱吗？
You remember that voice mail scofield prepaid for when he went off to prison?
-记得 -刚刚有人留言
- Yeah. - Someone just left a message on it.
-是谁？ -史柯菲
- Who? - Scofield.
他提到见面的事
Something about a meeting.
他好像在等某人去听留言 然后回电给他
Sounded like he's waiting for someone else to check the message, call him back.
这号码的开头，是手机号码 只要手机开着
This prefix, it's a cell phone number. As long as it's on...
就能追踪到他的位置
We can track exactly where he is.
不要做傻事K
Don't do anything stupid, don't do anything stupid.
有问题吗，警官？
Is there a problem, officer?
你知道我拦你下来的原因吗？
You know why I pulled you over today, sir?
超速？
Speeding?
麻烦给我看你的驾照和行照
Let me see your license and registration, please.
问题是我的皮夹不见了
The thing is, I lost my wallet.
那给我看行照就好
Well, I guess your registration will have to do just fine.
这是你的车，米勒太太？
So this is your car, Mrs. Miller?
米勒太太是我的妻子
Mrs. Miller's my wife.
我是米勒先生
I'm Mr. Miller.
你的牌照过期了
Well, your tags are expired.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
他招供了吗？
Did he sing?
什么都说了
Like a fat, sweaty bird.
小宝贝
Hey, sweet pea.
-爸爸 -过来
- Daddy. - Hey, come on.
瞧瞧你，长这么大了
Oh, look at you, you're so big.
帮我个忙，去拿一枝粉笔
I want you to do me a favor and grab a piece of chalk...
替爸爸在地上划图，好吗？
...draw Daddy a picture on the ground, okay?
你过得好吗？
So how you feeling, huh?
有好好吃东西吗？
You keeping your appetite up?
应该算有吧
Sort of, I guess.
那就好，很好
That's good. That's real good.
天啊，我真高兴见到你，宝贝
Oh, God, it's so good to see you, baby girl.
你知道爸爸现在的情况吗？
Do you understand what Daddy is going through right now?
大概知道 可是学校同学在说你的坏话
Sort of. But the kids at school have been saying stuff.
他们说什么？
Okay, what have they been saying?
他们说因为你是坏人 才会上电视
They're saying you're on TV because you're a bad man.
那你怎么想？
And what do you think?
如果我被关在一个地方
I think if I were some place...
他们不让我离开去找你
...and they wouldn't let me leave to see you...
我也不会乖乖听他们的话
...I wouldn't do what they said either.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我们很快就可以在一起
We are gonna be together real soon.
我向你保证
I promise you.
但爸爸要你帮一个忙
But Daddy needs you to do him a favor.
我要你传话给妈妈，好吗？
I need you to get a message to Mommy, okay?
好
Okay.
我要你告诉她 如果她了解我说的话
Now, I need you to tell her if she understood what I told her...
又愿意信任爸爸的话
...and if she is willing to trust Daddy...
就要在七点把门廊的灯打开
...that she needs to turn on the porch light at 7:00.
懂吗？你记得住吗？
Okay? Can you remember that?
真乖
That's a good girl.
蒂蒂，不要太靠近栅栏
Dede, stay away from the gate, honey.
爸爸要走了，好吗，宝贝？
Daddy gotta get going, okay, sweet pea?
-我爱你，爸爸 -我也爱你，宝贝
- I love you, Daddy. - I love you too, baby.
那里
There.
就快到了
It's not much further now.
好，他们下了州际公路 开上38号公路往北走
Okay, they've moved off the interstate, heading north on Route 38.
请说
Talk to me.
哪里？
Where? There's a patrolman who thinks...
宝州拉特罗布有个巡警 认为他拦下了费南多苏克
...he has Fernando sucre pulled over outside of Latrobe, Pennsylvania.
通知当地警局
Get in touch with the local dispatch.
说清楚我们要活捉，不要死捉
Make it clear that we want this man in custody, not in a body bag.
死人没办法透露 同伙在哪里，没错
Yeah, dead men can't tell us where their friends are. You got it.
-你确定是他吗？ -一定是，和照片一样
- Do you have a positive ID? - It's gotta be. It looks just like him.
-你能处理吗？ -可以
- Can you take care of it? - Yeah.
-好 -我会处理
- Okay, - I'll take care of it.
-请谨慎行事 -我会的
- Proceed with caution, - I will.
米勒先生
Mr. Miller...
我得请你把双手伸出车外
...I'm gonna have to ask you to place your arms outside the vehicle, please.
米勒先生，把手伸出来
Mr. Miller, I need to see some hands.
-准备好了吗？ -好了
- You ready? - Yeah.
就是现在
Now.
就是这里
This is the one.
-有看见他吗？ -没有，也许他没听到留言
- You see him? - Nope. Maybe he didn't get your message.
他们停下来了
They've stopped.
就在前面几里处，那里K
A couple of miles up ahead. There's...
那里什么也没有 他们在等什么？
There's nothing up there. What are they waiting on?
或是等谁？
Or who?
好，很好K
All right, that's good, that's good, that's good.
快点K
Oh, come on. Come on.
拿出警示灯K快点
Go red. Now! Go red!
还有一件事
There's one more thing.
你信任我吗？
You trust me?
当然
Of course.
要怎么做猎人才不会找足迹？
How do you throw the hunter off the scent?
除掉他的猎物
Get rid of the prey.
记住，我一按下“搜寻”按钮 30秒后它就会到103点7兆赫
Remember, once I hit scan, we'll have about 30 seconds before it reaches 103.7.
然后它会爆炸
Then she blows.
-没错，准备好了吗？ -好了
- That's right. Ready? - Yeah.
好，我们走
All right, let's go.
等等
Wait.
音乐没有变，等等K
The music's not changing. Wait, wait, wait.
不太对劲
Something's wrong.
怎么了？
What happened?
不知道，可是一定得爆炸才行
I don't know, but we're gonna need that explosion.
他来了
He's here.
收音机一定坏掉了 我们得亲自引爆炸弹
The radio must've jammed. We're gonna have to set it off manually.
那辆车随时可能会爆炸
The car could blow any second, Mike.
调查局员再过两分钟就到了
The feds are gonna be here in about two minutes.
要是我们不像死了 就真的死定了
If it doesn't look like we're dead, we will be.
剪刀石头布
Rock, paper, scissors.
-林克 -这次轮到我
- Linc. - It's my turn.
最好祈祷电台收得到
Better pray for reception.
102点1和103点7 之间有几个电台？
How many stations between 102.1 and 103.7?
在这荒郊野外？ 可能只有一个
Way out here? Just one, probably.
（纽约州，贝德福德斯图威桑特）
犸丽在哪里？
Where's Maricruz?
-听着K -不K彼提，你听着
- Hey, look, man... - No, no, no, Petey, you look.
我已经72小时没有麦眼
I haven't slept in 72 hours.
我眼见一个人的手被砍断
I've seen a man's hand get chopped off...
我被警察开枪、挖坟墓、偷车 跳上一台该死的火车
...I've been shot at, dug up a grave, stolen a car, jumped on a freaking train.
所以拜托你告诉我她在哪里
So please, just tell me where she is.
费南多，不要激动
Hey, Fernando, slow down, man.
我原本要告诉你 可是你把电话挂了
I was trying to tell you but you hung up the phone, man.
婚礼在拉斯维加斯
The wedding is in Vegas.
-赌城？ -对
- The city? - Yeah.
他们几小时前出发了，老哥
And they left a few hours ago, bro.
等等K不行K
Now, wait. No, no, no.
别这样，费南多
Come on, man. Hey, Fernando.
这车子是我的宝贝，这K
It's pristine, man. It's just...
我保证车子会安然还给你
Gonna be back to you in one piece, I promise.
你有听到我说“不行”吗？
Can we go back to the part where I said no?
-我没有选择余地 -你当然有选择
- I wish I had another choice. - You do have a choice.
拜托 它是1952年的乌拉尔机车
I mean, come on, man. It's a 1952 Ural motorbike.
-要是敢刮伤K -我不会刮伤的，我保证
- Bro, if you so much as scratch it... - I won't scratch it, I promise.
她是我一生的最爱
She's the love of my life, bro.
我非做点什么不可
I gotta do something.
-你看起来糟透了 -因为我去过地狱
- You look like hell, man. - Been through hell, papi.
现在我只要去赌城
Now, I just gotta get to Vegas.
大家好，我是莎拉，我K
Hi, I'm sara, and I...
过去几年 我和许多有毒瘾的人
over the years, I've worked with more than a few people...
一度共事过
...who had a history of addiction.
而K
And...
我会告诉他们 我能了解他们的感受
...I would tell them that I could understand what they were going through...
因为我曾经跟他们一样
...because I used to be just like them.
我曾经有过毒瘾
I used to be an addict too.
我想K
And I think...
我想现在我才真正看清的是
I think that what's becoming clear to me is that...
我了解他们的原因 是因为我跟他们一样
...the reason I understood them is because I am like them.
我以前从来没有毒瘾
I never used to be an addict.
我K
I...
大家好，我是莎拉，我有毒瘾
Hi, my name is sara and I'm an addict.
你好，莎拉
Hi, sara.
大家好，我是兰斯，我有毒瘾
Hi, my name's Lance and I'm an addict.
你好，兰斯
Hi, Lance.
莎拉说的很多话让我起了共鸣
I guess a lot of what sara just said resonates with me...
让我感同身受
...in what I'm going through.
这么辛苦计划，再逃出监狱
Put in all that work, break out of prison...
最后却死在河床底
...only to end up dead at the bottom of a ditch.
说真的有点悲哀
Kind of sad, really.
他是哥哥还是弟弟？
So which one of them was it?
席尔斯
Shales.
席尔斯？
Shales?
史柯菲，可能是史柯菲
Scofield. Might be scofield.
我看他哥哥的尸体也在里面吧
Probably gonna find his brother in there too.
奥斯卡席尔斯是 曼宏追捕很久的逃犯
Oscar shales is this guy Mahone tracked for a while.
他是个人渣，你知道那种人
Nasty little bottom feeder, you know the type.
他还在逃亡
He's still in the wind.
不可能每个都抓到，对吧？
Can't get them all, right?
现在前往犹他州的路没有阻碍了
We should have a pretty clear path to Utah now.
他们会把注意力转到其他人身上
They'll turn their attention to the other guys...
他们会有一阵子 不去注意我们
...which means we'll be off their radar for a while.
他们还是会检查 意外的鉴识报告
They're gonna get the lab results back from the accident.
到时我们已经到墨西哥了
We'll be in Mexico by then.
如果我们有交通工具的话
Provided the transport comes through.
快点，宝贝
Oh, come on, baby.
在彩虹厅
In the Rainbow Room,,,
你是否记得 我们拍照的美丽地点？
,,, do you remember that beautiful spot where we took that picture?
窗户旁边的地方？
The one by the window?
一个星期之后 我会在那里等着
I am gonna be waiting there in that spot one week from now,
她睡得好吗？
she sleeping okay?
很好，睡得很熟
Yeah, like a baby.
很好
Good.
你说你有丈夫的消息 要告诉我？
So you said you had some information you wanted to tell me about your husband?
看来我又要欠你一次人情了
Looks like I owe you another one.
-没关系 -好
- It's okay. - Okay.
我们到了墨西哥后 我会寄一万美金给你
Well, once we get to Mexico, I'll send you 10,000...
之前答应过的 外加车子的三千美金
...like I promised, plus another 3 for the car.
你会和她见面吗？ 那个医生？
Are you meeting up with her? Your doctor?
莎拉？
Sara?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们该走了 下个城镇有好几里远
We should get moving. Next town's a few miles away.
没关系 我到那里再搭公车回家
That's fine. I can catch a bus from there.
再次感谢你，妮卡
Thanks again, Nika.
我就知道，跟着那贱人 就能找到他们
I knew the little whore would take us right to them.